<root>
    <ability name="Archery">

        <charme>
            <title>
DRAGON-GRACED ARROW
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: On a successful Archery attack, the Dragon-Blooded
may also inflict an elemental effect appropriate to his aspect
on the target. Air will buffet the target, subtracting two dice
from her next action. Earth triggers a tremor beneath the
target’s feet, forcing her player to roll (Dexterity + Athletics),
difficulty 2, to avoid falling. Fire will set the target on fi re for
an action, dealing 4L damage. Water will fi ll the target’s lungs
with seawater, adding another three ticks before his next action
due to violent coughing. Wood will increase the damage of the
Dragon-Blooded’s arrow by 2L due the thorns covering it.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DRAGONFLY FINDS MATE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded may try to deflect an incoming
missile with an arrow of his own. The Exalt’s player rolls (Dexterity + Archery) and compares the results to the attacker’s
player’s roll. The attack is parried only if the Dragon-Blooded’s
successes equal or exceed the attacker’s.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
                HARVEST OF THE HUNTER
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: When this Charm is used, a plant of any kind near
the Dragon-Blooded will instantly sprout a number of arrows
equal to his Essence. The Dragon-Blooded can specify what
kind of arrows he wants.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SEVEN-YEAR SWARM VOLLEY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood must spend a base cost of 3 motes
and 1 Willpower plus 1 mote per person to be protected,
including himself. He must also have 2 arrows per person
handy. The Dragon-Blood’s player rolls (Dexterity + Archery), and until his next action, his successes are subtracted
from any ranged attacks made against the Dragon-Blood or
his allies. The Dragon-Blood cannot take multiple actions
when using this Charm.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SPARROW DIVES AT HAWK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m, 1wp
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: This Charm functions exactly like the Dragonfly
Finds Mate Charm (see above), except that if the DragonBlood’s player’s successes on her (Dexterity + Archery) roll
exceed those of her enemy, the remaining successes are
applied as an Archery attack against that enemy. This is
treated as a counterattack.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SWALLOWS DEFEND THE NEST
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m/arrow
Type: Extra Action
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Archery 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can fire additional arrows in an
attack, adding one arrow per mote spent up to the maximum
of his Essence. Each arrow is fi red with the Dragon-Blood’s
full dice pool.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>


    <ability name="Athletics">

        <charme>
            <title>
BELLOWS-PUMPING STRIDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Athletics 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For a scene, the Dragon-Blooded can double his
movement rate on all Move and Dash actions.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
EFFORTLESSLY RISING FLAME
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Athletics 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded may instantly rise from a prone
position or add two dice to his Athletics rating for the purposes of calculating jumping distance.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FALLING STAR MANEUVER
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per 2 dice
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Athletics 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded can move more gracefully
in combat. Each mote spent (up to the maximum of her
permanent Essence) adds two dice of damage to a successful
hand-to-hand attack.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Awareness">

        <charme>
            <title>
                ALL-ENCOMPASSING EARTH SENSE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Awareness 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While the Charm is in effect, the Dragon-Blood cannot
be surprised by any means. The Dragon-Blood may extend this
benefi t to companions at a cost of 2 extra motes per person.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FEELING THE DRAGON’S BONES
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Awareness 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: So long as the Dragon-Blooded is touching the
ground (or in a building doing so), she can sense anything
else resting on the ground in a radius of (Awareness x 25)
feet. The Dragon-Blood’s player must successfully roll (Intelligence + Awareness) to do so, gaining more information
with more successes.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Bureaucracy">

        <charme>
            <title>
BENEVOLENT MASTER’S BLESSING
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Bureaucracy 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: For 1 mote per two dice, the Dragon-Blood can increase the Bureaucracy Ability of a trusted underling or for 1
mote, he can divide his own Bureaucracy Ability dots among
a group of underlings with no Bureaucracy Ability dots. The
Dragon-Blooded cannot give out more dice than he has or
more than double an underling’s Bureaucracy Ability.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
CONFLUENCE OF SAVANT THOUGHT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Bureaucracy 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may instantly understand the inner
workings of the bureaucracy with which she is confronted,
knowing such details as who is in charge and where things
are kept. She may also substitute her Bureaucracy for her
Socialize Ability for Bureaucracy-related purposes.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THOUGHTFUL GIFT TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Bureaucracy 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: With a successful (Perception + Bureaucracy) roll,
the Dragon-Blood can intuit what would be the perfect gift
CHAPTER ONE • THE DRAGON-BLOODED 19
— or the perfect bribe. However, the Charm does not provide
the gift, or even easy access to it, but simply the knowledge
of what sort of gift would secure a favorable response.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THRASHING CARP SERENADE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Bureaucracy 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may bring any bureaucratic or
administrative tasks going on within the sound of his voice
to a standstill. The player of anyone attempting to succeed
on a Bureaucracy roll must overcome the Dragon-Blood in
an opposed (Stamina + Bureaucracy) roll.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Craft">

        <charme>
            <title>
FLAW-FINDING EXAMINATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One minute
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Craft 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may attempt to fi nd the weak spot
in some object, spending 1 mote for items she can touch or 3
motes for items she can only observe. While the Dragon-Blood
may then attempt to cure the fl aw, she will more often use
the Charm to exploit it. Any damage inflicted on her next
successful physical attack against the object will be doubled.
If used against armor or a weapon, treat this as a disarming
attempt, with a success destroying the item.
            </inner>
        </charme>


        <charme>
            <title>
SHAPING HAND STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One hour
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Craft 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded can enchant one of his hands
so that it will perform the tasks of a tool — a pick axe, a
hatchet, a hammer, etc. — while still functioning normally
as a hand.
            </inner>
        </charme>


    </ability>
    <ability name="Dodge">
        <charme>
            <title>
HOPPING FIRECRACKER EVASION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Dodge 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: If the Dragon-Blood’s player succeeds on a (Dexterity
+ Dodge) roll, she can dash up to ([Dexterity + 6 – wound
penalties – mobility penalty) yards as a free action. This
will usually take her out of hand-to-hand combat range,
and allow her to evade most multiple attack Charms after
the fi rst attack.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SMOKE OBSCURING EFFECT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Dodge 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can create an elemental effect
— usually smoke, but possibly fog, dust or even swirling leaves
— that distracts his enemies and gives his allies a greater
opportunity to dodge attacks. Regardless of the nature of the
distraction, the mechanical effect is the same: the DragonBlood must spend 1 mote per ally (up to a maximum of his
Essence) and an additional 1 mote for every point by which
each ally increases his DDV (up to the maximum of the
Dragon-Blood’s own Dodge rating or double any particular
ally’s Dodge rating, whichever is less).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THRESHOLD WARDING STANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Dodge 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: For the duration of one action, the Dragon-Blood
can ignore all environmental penalties to her DDV, even in
places where dodging would seemingly be impossible, such
as on tree limbs or up to her knees in quicksand.
            </inner>
        </charme>


        <charme>
            <title>
VIRTUOUS NEGATION DEFENSE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Dodge 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: If an ally within normal leaping distance (about fi ve
yards) is subject to an attack, the Dragon-Blood can attempt
to move her out of the way. The Dragon-Blood’s player must
fi rst roll (Dexterity + Dodge). If he scores no successes, the
attack proceeds normally. If he scores any successes, the
Exalt can make himself the target of the attack instead of
the ally. If his successes exceed half the attack dice pool,
both the Dragon-Blooded and the ally automatically dodge
without a roll.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Integrity">
        <charme>
            <title>
INVIOLATE DRAGON SPIRIT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m, 1wp, 1hl
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Integrity 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can instantly overcome the effects
of any natural or unnatural compulsion. Most commonly used
to instantly break the hold of narcotic or similar addictions
without going through a lengthy withdrawal, the Charm can
also act as a perfect parry against any Social attack, including those that incorporate unnatural Mental influence. The
Willpower point spent on this Charm does not count toward
the two-point maximum on Willpower points that must be
spent within a scene (see Exalted, p. 180).
            </inner>
        </charme>


         <charme>
            <title>
OATH OF THE TEN-THOUSAND DRAGONS
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: —
Type: Permanent
Duration: Permanent
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Integrity 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood holds a heightened sense of loyalty to a particular group of people (just as Righteous Lion
Defense grants a Solar a heightened sense of loyalty to an
ideal). The group may be the Dragon-Blood’s Great House,
her unit or ministry, her sworn brotherhood or even the
Dragon-Blooded as a whole, although there is obvious danger
in becoming preternaturally loyal to very large populations.
When the Dragon-Blood is confronted by Social attacks that
go against her loyalty to her chosen group, she automatically
adds her Integrity to her Mental Defense Value.
            </inner>
        </charme>


        <charme>
            <title>
TEN-THOUSAND DRAGONS FIGHT AS ONE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Integrity 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For the duration of a scene, a Dragon-Blood can
instantly dedicate himself to a new Intimacy — loyalty to
another Dragon-Blood in his immediate vicinity. By doing so,
the Dragon-Blood using this Charm may treat the loyalty as
an additional Intimacy, with all the benefi ts and drawbacks
thereof. There need be no particular form of connection
between the Dragon-Blood and his new Intimacy — indeed,
he may not even know her name — but the fact that she is
a fellow Terrestrial Exalt is a source of comfort and strength
to him. A Dragon-Blood may only forge a number of new
Intimacies equal to his Conviction during a given scene.
            </inner>
        </charme>



    </ability>

    <ability name="Investigation">
        <charme>
            <title>
BLOODHOUND’S NOSE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 6m/1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Investigation 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: After spending 10 minutes walking around a crime
scene and then finding any evidence with a successful (Intelligence + Investigation) roll, the Dragon-Blooded can trace
the evidence back to who left it.
            </inner>
        </charme>


        <charme>
            <title>
HOMEWARD TRAIL DISCOVERY METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m/1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Investigation 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: By simply meeting someone and coming with a few
yards of him, the Dragon-Blooded can instantly know where
the person’s home is.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
REVELATION OF ASSOCIATES HUNCH
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m/1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Investigation 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: Upon meeting someone, the Dragon-Blood can gain
an intuitive knowledge of the person’s closest associates.
Each success on a (Perception + Investigation) roll gives the
Dragon-Blood the name and a one-sentence description of
one of the target’s allies, contacts or employers, beginning
with those most important to the target.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SCENT-OF-CRIME METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Investigation 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: By spending Essence and rolling (Manipulation
+ Investigation), the Dragon-Blood can tell which of the
people currently before him is the most guilty. This is purely
subjective; the guilty party the Dragon-Blood seeks might
feel no guilt over her actions, while someone else might feel
intensely guilty for some unrelated crime.
            </inner>
        </charme>



    </ability>

    <ability name="Larceny">
        <charme>
            <title>
EARS OF THE SNOWY OWL
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Simple
Duration: One minute
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Larceny 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While this Charm is in effect, the Dragon-Blooded
can hear conversations going on in adjacent rooms as if there
were no walls in place, ignoring any penalties associated with
obstacles between her and the objects of her attention.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
OBSERVER AWARENESS METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Refl exive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Larceny 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: With just one success on a (Perception + Larceny)
roll, the Dragon-Blooded will instantly know if he is being
watched. Additional successes will pinpoint the specific
location of observers.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
TRACKLESS WALK STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Larceny 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While this Charm is in effect, the Dragon-Blooded
will leave no clues to her identity at a location, such as a crime
scene or the like. The Charm does not prevent supernatural
tracking attempts.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Linguistics">

        <charme>
            <title>
LANGUAGE-LEARNING RITUAL
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m/1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One week
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Linguistics 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can become completely fluent in
a foreign language after listening to it for an hour, mastering
conversation and literacy
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
POISONED TONGUE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m/1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Concentration
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Linguistics 3
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can manipulate a conversation
she overhears, causing other listeners to hear what she desires
instead of what was actually said. The Exalt’s player must roll
(Manipulation + Linguistics), with the successes determining the level of control. Participants in the conversation
may notice the effect with a reflexive (Wits + Perception)
roll made by their players against a difficulty equal to the
Dragon-Blood’s Essence.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THOUSAND TONGUES MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Linguistics 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For the duration, the Dragon-Blood can speak and
understand any spoken foreign language. However, communication is limited; the Dragon-Blood’s social and communicative
actions are at a -4 penalty, reduced by 1 for each point of
permanent Essence by which she exceeds the minimum.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Lore">

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL BOLT ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per 2L
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Lore 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can fi re a bolt of elemental energy
appropriate to her aspect from her hand toward a target. The
bolt is targeted with (Dexterity + Athletics) or (Dexterity
+ Archery), whichever is preferred, with an accuracy bonus
equal to the Dragon-Blood’s Essence and a range of (Essence
x 20) yards. The bolt inflicts 2L damage per mote spent, up
to a maximum number of motes equal to the Dragon-Blood’s
Stamina. At the Storyteller’s discretion, depending on the
elemental type, the attack might also have “special effects,”
such as a water bolt extinguishing a small fi re or a fi re bolt
igniting flammable material.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL BURST TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per 1L
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Lore 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: As per Elemental Bolt Attack (see above) except that
the Charm produces an elemental burst with a radius equal
to the Dragon-Blood’s Essence in yards and the damage is
only 1L per mote spent.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL EMPOWERMENT MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1+ wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Lore 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can draw Essence directly from his
element, regaining a number of motes equal to his Lore Ability for every Willpower point spent. If the Dragon-Blooded
spends more Willpower points in a day than his Essence,
each additional use of Willpower for this Charm will also
inflict one level of unsoakable bashing damage.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Martial Arts">

        <charme>
            <title>
AIR DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: After a successful (Dexterity + Martial Arts) roll
to activate the form, the Immaculate can add her Martial
Arts to any ranged attack, up to the maximum of doubling
her normal Archery or Thrown Ability. Also, her DDV is
increased by half of her Martial Arts rating for the scene.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
AIR DRAGON’S SIGHT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Immaculate cannot be surprised or ambushed, and
when this Charm is used outside of combat, his player may
add the Dragon-Blood’s Essence to any Awareness roll.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
AVENGING WIND STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: In a successful attack, in addition to taking damage as normal, the target’s player must make a reflexive
(Strength + Athletics) roll for the target. The target will be
knocked back 10 yards for every dot the Immaculate has in
Martial Arts minus fi ve yards per success on the (Strength
+ Athletics) roll.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
BREATH-SEIZING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: On a successful strike, instead of rolling damage, roll
the Immaculate’s (Strength + Martial Arts), opposed by the
target’s (Stamina + Resistance). Each net success inflicts a
cumulative -1 internal penalty on the target; if penalties ever
double the target’s Stamina, she is rendered unconscious.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
CLOUD TREADING METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: While the Charm is in effect, the Immaculate’s
movement rate and leaping distance are doubled, and he
no longer needs to touch solid ground (allowing him to run
up smoke trails, for example). He must remain moving or
gravity takes over, but he is otherwise free to act.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
HURRICANE COMBAT METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m, 1wp + 1hl per action
Type: Refl exive
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: For up to (Martial Arts) actions, the Immaculate
can increase her DDV by half her Martial Arts and half the
speed of any Martial Arts attacks she makes. She can also
triple her movement and double her jumping height, and,
additionally, she can make a number of extra attacks (Martial
Arts or ranged) per action equal to her Essence. Willpower
and motes are paid up front, and at the end of the Charm’s
duration, the Immaculate takes one level of unsoakable
bashing damage for each action the Charm lasted.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
LIGHTNING STRIKE STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m, 1hl
Type: Simple
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate can make martial arts attacks at a
distance of (Essence x 10) feet, inflicting (Strength + Essence)
in lethal electrical damage. Martial arts weapons add to ac-
CHAPTER ONE • THE DRAGON-BLOODED 23
curacy and damage as normal, but the Immaculate must pay
1 extra mote for using any weapon other than a chakram.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SHROUDING THE BODY AND MIND
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate can render himself virtually invisible for a number of actions equal to his Martial Arts rating.
Onlookers attempting to spot the Immaculate must roll
(Perception + Awareness), at a difficulty ranging from 1 for
onlookers who saw him disappear to 5 for people with no
reason to suspect his presence. Additionally, for every action
the Immaculate evades detection, the difficulty to spot him
increases, up to a maximum of 5.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THUNDERCLAP KATA
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate can clap her hands together to create
a thunderclap. The player of anyone within (Essence x 10)
yards of the Immaculate must make a reflexive (Stamina +
Resistance) roll for his character with a difficulty equal to
the Immaculate’s Essence. If successful, the target will lose
his next action but suffer no further penalty. Otherwise, the
attack inflicts (Strength + Martial Arts) bashing damage,
which cannot be soaked with armor. The attack also deafens
the target for a number of actions equal to the Immaculate’s
Essence, and the target loses (Essence) dice from all dice
pools due to disorientation. The Immaculate can render
select persons immune to the Charm’s effects at a cost of 1
mote per person.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
TORNADO OFFENSE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m per attack
Type: Extra Action
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While performing a flurry, for every 3 motes spent,
the Immaculate may make one additional ranged or Martial
Arts attack with his full dice pool. The total number of attacks cannot exceed his Martial Arts Ability.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WIND DRAGON SPEED
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: On the Immaculate’s next Martial Arts attack, her
attack’s speed is reduced by her Martial Arts rating (to a
minimum of 1), and its DV penalty is only -1.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WRATHFUL WINDS MANEUVER
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate utters a shout, unleashing a gale-force
blast from his mouth in a 90-degree arc, out to a distance
of (Essence x 10) feet. The player of anyone in the area of
effect must make a (Strength + Athletics) roll to avoid her
character being knocked down (difficulty is equal to the
Immaculate’s Martial Arts) and a (Wits + Resistance) roll to
avoid her character being stunned for her next action. The
Immaculate may also spend a point of Willpower to focus
the shout on a single target (who cannot avoid the attack
without an impenetrable defense), inflicting (Strength +
Essence) lethal damage, which bypasses armor. In addition,
the difficulty to avoid knockdown for a single target is equal
to (the Immaculate’s Strength + Essence).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
AVALANCHE METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Special
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: On a successful bare-handed attack by the Immaculate,
his player can make a (Strength + Martial Arts) roll resisted
by the target’s (Stamina + Athletics). If the Immaculate wins
or ties, then, in addition to the normal damage inflicted, each
success subtracts one die from all dice pools for physical actions
so long as the Immaculate can see the target. If the successes
exceed the target’s Stamina, the target is completely immobilized, but only so long the Immaculate maintains physical
contact with her. As long as the Immaculate can maintain
the proper contact, the Charm can last indefinitely.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
EARTH DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate’s player must fi rst succeed in a (Dexterity + Martial Arts) roll for the Dragon-Blood to assume
the Earth Dragon Form. Thereafter, she can add her Martial
Arts to her bashing and lethal soak and can soak aggravated
damage with her Martial Arts.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
EARTHSHAKER ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: While standing on an earthen surface, the Immaculate
stamps her foot, and the players of everyone within (Essence x 10) feet must make (Dexterity + Resistance) rolls
with a diffi culty of the Immaculate’s Essence to avoid their
characters being knocked down. Anyone knocked down
will take bashing damage equal to the Immaculate’s Martial
Arts, soaked as normal.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FORCE OF THE MOUNTAIN
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Immaculate can add his Essence to the damage
of the next Melee or Martial Arts attack he lands. If using a
melee weapon other than one of the Earth Dragon’s signature weapons — the sledge or tetsubo — he must spend an
additional mote of Essence.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
HUNGRY EARTH STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5+m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate must strike the earth with an open
palm. Immediately thereafter, the ground beneath her target
will open up beneath her feet and then slam shut, immobilizing
her. The Immaculate’s player must roll (Strength + Martial
Arts) in a reflexive opposed roll against the target’s (Wits
+ Athletics). Each net success for the Immaculate adds 1
to the difficulty of all rolls for physical actions made for the
target. The target cannot move until her player succeeds in
a (Strength + Athletics) roll with a difficulty equal to the
Immaculate’s net successes, which requires a full action. If
the Immaculate’s net successes exceed the target’s Strength,
the target is sucked all the way into the ground, and the net
successes are considered to be doubled when the target attempts escape. The Immaculate can target multiple enemies
for 1 mote per extra target up to a maximum of double her
Essence.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
PERFECTION OF EARTH BODY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 5
Effect: After a moment’s concentration, the Immaculate
transforms his body into living stone. His Strength is doubled,
and his hand-to-hand attacks cause lethal damage. Also, he
adds his Essence to his accuracy, damage and defense values,
and he soaks lethal damage with his entire Stamina and adds
his Essence score to his bashing soak. Finally, the Immaculate
can ignore all wound penalties for the Charm’s duration. This
Charm is incompatible with armor.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SHATTERING FIST STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: (Martial Arts) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For the duration of the Charm, any damage the
Immaculate inflicts on objects (but not living things) is
doubled.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
STILLNESS OF STONE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Special
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: If the Immaculate successfully harms a target with a
bare-handed attack, the target will be paralyzed and rendered
Inactive for fi ve ticks per level of damage infl icted. If the
target is slain, her body will turn to stone.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
STONE DRAGON’S SKIN
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Refl exive
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate can add his Martial Arts Ability as
armor against lethal and bashing damage until his next action
and can also parry weapons with his bare hands.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
UNMOVING MOUNTAIN STANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: (Martial Arts) minutes
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Immaculate can add her Essence in automatic
successes to any attempt to resist being moved or knocked
down and to any attempt to avoid being discovered or located
while she is not moving
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WEAPON-BREAKING DEFENSE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Special
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate may parry either bare-handed or with a
weapon. If successful, his player can make a refl exive (Strength
+ Martial Arts) roll for the Dragon-Blood to destroy the weapon.
The difficulty is 1 for normal weapons, 3 for exceptional
weapons and 5 for weapons forged of magical materials. Even
if the Immaculate fails to destroy the weapon, its bearer’s player
must succeed in a reflexive opposed (Strength + Athletics) roll
against the Immaculate’s player or her character is disarmed.
The Essence cost of the Charm is equal to the difficulty to
destroy the weapon and is paid before the attempt.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
BREATH OF THE FIRE DRAGON
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate can spit a gout of fl ame up to (Essence) yards. The attack roll is her (Perception + Martial
Arts), adding her Essence as automatic successes. For every
mote spent (up to the maximum of her Martial Arts), the
attack inflicts Essence in lethal damage dice.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
CONSUMING MIGHT OF THE FIRE DRAGON
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 6m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: For an Aspect of Fire using this Charm, the effects of
his anima power are tripled. For non-Fire Aspects, the Charm
allows the Immaculate to use the Fire Aspect anima power
at its normal level. Also, anyone viewing the Immaculate,
regardless of his aspect, is affected as if by the Overwhelming Fire Majesty Stance (see below) except that the effects
last for an entire scene and the Immaculate is free to attack
and/or use Charms.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ESSENCE-IGNITING NERVE STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: On a successful strike, the target does not take normal
damage, but instead takes one level of lethal damage for every mote of Essence in her Personal Essence pool, up to the
maximum of twice the Immaculate’s permanent Essence. The
damage ignores armor but can otherwise be soaked normally.
This Charm does not affect the Essence motes in the target
but simply uses them as a catalyst for damage.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIERY HAND ATTACK 
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: On a successful Martial Arts strike, the Immaculate
adds his Ability rating in damage, and all damage inflicted
26
is lethal. Additionally, the Immaculate’s player reflexively
rolls (Strength + Martial Arts), resisted by the target’s
(Stamina + Resistance). If the Immaculate’s player succeeds, the target will also burst into fl ame that can only
be doused by magic and that will inflict 6L per action for
(Martial Arts) actions. Targets can reduce damage to 2L
each action with a successful (Stamina + Resistance) roll
at difficulty 3.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIRE DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate’s player must successfully roll
(Dexterity + Martial Arts) for the Dragon-Blood to invoke
the form. For the remainder of the scene, the Immaculate
increases her DDV by half of her Martial Arts Ability. Also,
the Immaculate’s bashing attacks inflict lethal damage instead
due to tremendous heat.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FLAME-FLICKER STANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Reflexive
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For each mote the Immaculate spends (up to the
maximum of her permanent Essence), her active DV increases by 1.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FLASH-FIRE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Immaculate may reroll his Join Battle roll and
take the best of the two results.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
OVERWHELMING FIRE MAJESTY STANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: While the Immaculate maintains the stance, anyone trying to attack her must subtract her Martial Arts
from his dice pool when doing so. Anyone trying to attack
one clearly allied with the Immaculate must subtract half
that number, up to a range of the Immaculate’s Essence in
yards. The Immaculate can defend herself and take normal
actions but cannot make attacks or use other Charms while
maintaining the stance; the effect lingers for three ticks after
the stance is dropped.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SEARING FIST ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: When the Dragon-Blooded inflicts damage on his
target with a Martial Arts blow and activates this Charm,
the Dragon-Blooded causes a searing pain in his target that
infl icts a -1 penalty to the target’s dice pools for the remainder of the scene. This penalty is in addition to any other
wound penalties, and additional uses of this Charm have a
cumulative effect.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SMOLDERING WOUND ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: If the Immaculate successfully damages her opponent,
then, on her following action, the post-soak damage is rolled
again. No soak is applied to the second action.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON BLOCKING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood increases his PDV by half of his
permanent Essence. If unarmed, he can parry lethal attacks
without a stunt.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON CLAW
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood inflicts lethal damage instead of
bashing on an unarmed attack.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON FIST
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 6m, 1wp, 1hl
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can make a single punch or kick
that inflicts aggravated damage. This Charm cannot be
channeled through a weapon.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON-FORCE BLOW
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may double the normal base damage
from an attack (but not extra successes) before subtracting
soak. Also, the attack may knock her opponent down and
stun him for one action with a successful (Strength + Martial
Arts) roll made by the Dragon-Blood’s player, resisted by the
target’s (Strength + Resistance).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood inflicts lethal damage with her
Martial Arts attacks instead of bashing and soaks lethal damage with her full bashing soak. Also, she can add her Essence
to her Dexterity or Strength for determining running speed,
jumping distance or feats of strength.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON FORTITUDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per 2B or 1L
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may augment his soak against
a specific attack, at a cost of 1 mote per two bashing or 1
mote per one lethal. This soak is compatible with the use
of armor.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON INVULNERABILITY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m, 1wp
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: When the Charm is used, the Dragon-Blood can
ignore all damage from a single non-magical attack. Against
magical attacks (including weapons made of the fi ve magical
materials), the Dragon-Blood receives a soak bonus equal
to (Essence).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FIVE-DRAGON WRATH
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per attack + 1hl
Type: Extra Action
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can make one extra attack per mote
spent at his full attack dice pool. The maximum number of
attacks is equal to (Essence), and the defender’s player may
make only one dodge and/or parry roll, which is compared to
all attacks. Using this Charm inflicts one level of unsoakable
bashing damage on the Dragon-Blood.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
BECOME THE HAMMER
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded’s unarmed attack inflicts lethal
damage.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
BLADE-DEFLECTING PALM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Refl exive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: Even if unarmed, the Dragon-Blooded can apply
his PDV to any Martial Arts or Melee attacks that inflict
lethal damage.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FLOW PAST DEFENSES
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m + 2m per action
Type: Supplemental
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: If the Dragon-Blooded successfully puts her opponent
into a clinch, her net successes on the initial attack roll are
28
subtracted from the target’s soak for the next action. She
can continue to use this Charm, paying 2 motes per action
until the target breaks free or is released.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
POUNDING SURF STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: On a successful hand-to-hand attack, the DragonBlooded ignores one point of the target’s soak. Each successive
time this Charm is used in a scene, the Dragon-Blooded
ignores one additional point of soak. No other attacker gains
the benefit of this cumulative soak reduction.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
BOTTOMLESS DEPTHS DEFENSE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m, 1hl
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: When this Charm is activated, the Immaculate immediately takes one level of aggravated damage, but ignores
all other damage inflicted on him from a single attack.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
CRASHING WAVE STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Extra Action
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: On a successful Martial Arts attack, the Immaculate
who invokes this Charm may make a second attack at -1
die to his pool. If the second attack succeeds, he can make a
third attack at -2 and a fourth at -4. The die penalty doubles
on each subsequent attack, and the Charm ends when the
Immaculate fails an attack, his dice pool is reduced to zero
or the number of attacks equals his Martial Arts.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DROWNING-IN-BLOOD TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate must make a successful Martial Arts
attack that does not inflict damage on the target. Instead, the
Immaculate’s player rolls (Strength + Martial Arts), opposed
by the target’s (Stamina + Resistance). If the Immaculate
wins, the target suffers internal bleeding and loses one dot of
Stamina for a number of actions equal to the Immaculate’s
extra successes. Subsequent uses of the Charm are cumulative,
and a target reduced to zero Stamina is dead.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ESSENCE-DOUSING WAVE ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 8m, 1wp
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: The Immaculate makes a normal Martial Arts attack. If she inflicts damage, the Immaculate’s player makes
an immediate reflexive (Essence + Martial Arts) roll with a
difficulty of half the target’s Essence. For three ticks per success, any Charms or spells affecting the target are neutralized.
If the number of successes exceeds the Essence of whoever
invoked the Charm or cast the spell, the magic is completely
dispelled. Charms and spells can be reactivated during this
Charm’s duration, however.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FLOW REVERSAL STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate makes an unarmed Martial Arts attack that does normal damage. In addition, the target’s player
must roll (Stamina + Resistance), as all the blood in the
target’s veins reverses direction for an instant. The difficulty
of the roll is equal to the Immaculate’s successes on the initial
attack roll, unreduced by any dodge or parry successes. If an
Exalted target fails to exceed those successes, he takes one
level of unsoakable lethal damage. Even if he succeeds, his
player must subtract two dice from all rolls for a number of
actions equal to the Immaculate’s Martial Arts. Mortals are
slain outright if the (Stamina + Resistance) roll fails.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FLOWING WATER DEFENSE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Refl exive
Duration: (Essence) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: While the Charm is in effect, the Immaculate subtracts
one die from all attack pools, while anyone trying to attack
her will subtract three dice from all attack pools.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
RIPPLING WATER STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate attacks a target as normal. In addition
to the normal damage inflicted on the primary target, the Immaculate also infl icts a number of dice of bashing damage on
everyone else within 10 feet of the target equal to the number
of damage successes inflicted on the primary target.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SHRUGGING WATER DRAGON ESCAPE

            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Immaculate with this Charm cannot be restrained.
Mundane chains shatter, ropes snap and handcuffs drop away.
The effects of supernatural restraints are nullified for (the
Immaculate’s Martial Arts x 3) ticks.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THEFT-OF-ESSENCE METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m, 1wp
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: After a successful attack, the Immaculate’s player
rolls (Essence + Martial Arts), stealing 3 motes of Essence
for each success from his target and adding to his own reserve. The Essence gained from this Charm fades at a rate
of 1 mote per minute.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
TSUNAMI FORCE SHOUT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m, 1wp, 1hl
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: The Tsunami Force Shout radiates out from the Immaculate in a 45-degree arc extending out (Essence) yards,
inflicting ([Essence + Martial Arts] x 2) damage. The player of
anyone within the area of effect must make a reflexive Essence
roll. On a botch, the damage for that target is aggravated,
and any damage not soaked is an automatic success. If the
Essence roll fails, the damage is aggravated but soaked and
rolled normally. If the roll succeeds, the damage is lethal and
rolled normally. With three or more successes on the Essence
roll, the damage is bashing
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WATER DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate’s player must succeed on a (Dexterity
+ Martial Arts) roll for the Exalt to activate the Water Dragon
Form. Thereafter, she receives a bashing and lethal soak bonus
equal to her Martial Arts and can soak lethal damage with
her full Stamina. Also, when successfully attacked, she can
further augment her soak reflexively by spending 1 mote per
two points of soak. This only applies to a single attack, and
the Essence must be spent before the attacker rolls damage.
Finally, the Charm adds the Immaculate’s Essence to her
Martial Arts Ability for the Charm’s duration.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DEATH-PATTERN SENSING ATTITUDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: To activate this Charm, the Immaculate must spend
a base cost of 5 motes and 1 Willpower. Thereafter, she can
apply her full DDV to any attacks launched against her at a
cost of 1 mote, up to a maximum number of dodges between
action ticks equal to her Essence. However, she can only
dodge attacks by beings with a spirit (including undead).
She cannot dodge traps, falling rocks or attacks by automata.
Finally, she cannot dodge ranged attacks made from beyond
a radius of her Essence in yards.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ENTHRALLING BLOW ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 8m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate must make a successful Martial
Arts attack on her target. Instead of rolling damage, her
player must reflexively roll the Exalt’s (Essence + Martial
Arts) opposed by the target’s (Essence + Integrity). If the
Immaculate wins, the target is enthralled, losing his next
action. In subsequent actions, the target’s player can attempt
to have the target shake off the effects by rolling (Essence
+ Integrity) at a difficulty of (1 + the successes rolled by the
30
Immaculate’s player on the opposed roll). This Charm only
works on living creatures.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
EYES OF THE WOOD DRAGON
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: Special
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: After invoking this Charm, the Immaculate must
successfully attack his target within fi ve actions or the Essence is wasted. On a successful attack, the Immaculate’s
player rolls his character’s Essence as extra damage dice.
These extra damage dice bypass the target’s armor.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
MIND-OVER-BODY MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m per hl
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For every 2 motes spent, the Immaculate can heal
one level of bashing damage inflicted upon him.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SOUL-MARKING STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: To enact this Charm, the Immaculate must successfully
touch his opponent and spend the Essence. The target feels a
sharp pain in her head but nothing more. For the remainder
of the scene, however, the Immaculate gains an automatic
success on any attack rolls made against a target who has
been branded. Multiple soul mark effects are cumulative.
For 24 hours after branding a target, the Immaculate can
sense when a branded being is within (Essence) yards and
which being it is.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SOUL MASTERY
            </title>
            <inner>
SOUL MASTERYCost: 10m, 1hl
Type: Simple
Duration: (Essence) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: After activating this Charm, a black aura will linger
on the Immaculate’s hands for (Essence) actions. During
that time, the Immaculate must successfully touch his target,
either casually or as part of a hand-to-hand attack inflicting
normal damage. Upon touching a target, the Immaculate’s
player makes a reflexive (Essence + Martial Arts) roll against
the opponent’s (Stamina + Integrity). If the target loses, she
is instantly slain. Even if she wins, the attack still inflicts
aggravated damage dice equal to the Immaculate’s Essence.
If the Immaculate fails to touch another target within the
time allotted by the Charm, the Immaculate will suffer the
effects of the Charm himself.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
UNBREAKABLE FASCINATION KATA
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Simple
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: As long as the Immaculate continues to exercise
the kata, the player of anyone attempting to do anything
other than stare at him with rapt fascination must successfully roll her character’s (Wits + Integrity), opposed by the
Immaculate’s (Charisma + Martial Arts). While executing
the kata, the Immaculate may speak, move at half pace or
dodge. Any other action ends the Charm.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WOOD DRAGON FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate’s player must successful roll (Dexterity
+ Martial Arts) for his character to invoke the Wood Dragon
Form. Thereafter, he regenerates one health level of bashing
damage every action and one health level of lethal damage every
other action. If slain, he does not continue regenerating.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WOOD DRAGON SUCCOR
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m per hl
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Immaculate can heal others by drawing their
wounds into her own body. By touching the injured target
and spending the required Essence, the Dragon-Blooded can
heal any type of injury but immediately suffers those injuries
herself. She can, of course, heal those injuries herself with
Wood Dragon Form, unless they are aggravated.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WOOD DRAGON VITALITY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Martial Arts 3
Minimum Essence: 2
CHAPTER 31 ONE • THE DRAGON-BLOODED
Effect: Until his next action, the Immaculate’s bashing soak
is boosted by his Martial Arts rating, and he can soak lethal
damage with his full Stamina.
            </inner>

        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Medicine">

        <charme>
            <title>
DISEASE-BANISHING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Medicine 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can cure any non-magical disease she has successfully diagnosed (see Exalted, p. 137)
with a touch.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DREAD INFECTION STRIKE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Medicine 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can enchant
her weapon so that any wounds it causes
are much more likely to become infected.
After this Charm is invoked, the difficulty
to resist infection from one of the DragonBlood’s hits increases by 2. The Essence
must be spent before the attack roll, and
the attack must infl ict at least one health
level of lethal damage.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
INFECTION-BANISHING PRANA
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Medicine 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can instantly
cure any infection (although not the wounds
that actually became infected). Furthermore, wounded persons treated with this
Charm will not become infected under any
circumstances, at least in any wounds they
had when the Charm was used.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WOUND-CLOSING TOUCH
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Medicine 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: For 1 mote, the Dragon-Blood can instantly staunch
the bleeding of herself or another. The Dragon-Blood can
also convert lethal wounds into bashing wounds for herself
or others at a cost of 2 motes per damage level.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Melee">
        <charme>
            <title>
DEADLY WILDFIRE LEGION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can increase the Melee Ability
ratings of his allies, at a cost of 1 mote per two dice (to a
maximum of the Dragon-Blood’s Melee rating or double each
ally’s individual rating) plus 1 mote per ally affected.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DRAGON-GRACED WEAPON
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: Per Dragon-Graced Arrow (see p. 17), except that the
Charm supplements Melee attacks instead of Archery attacks.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
PORTENTOUS COMET DEFLECTING MODE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m, 1wp
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: After an opponent’s hand-to-hand attack, roll
(Dexterity + Melee). Regardless of the attacker’s successes,
if the Dragon-Blood achieves even one success, the attack is
totally blocked. However, this Charm will not block sorcerous
attacks or attacks enhanced by Charms.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
REFINING THE INNER BLADE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: With a moment’s concentration, the Dragon-Blood
can conjure a sword fashioned entirely from the element to
which she is aspected. The weapon has the stats of a normal
weapon of its type, as well as the benefits conferred by the
Dragon-Graced Weapon Charm (see above).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
RINGING ANVIL ONSLAUGHT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 8m
Type: Extra Action
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded can focus his attention on a
single target and roll his unmodified Melee Ability. Each
success allows the Dragon-Blooded to make one extra
Melee attack against that target as part of a flurry, up to the
maximum of his Melee Ability
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
THRESHING FLOOR TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One attack
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Melee 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded can overcome the normal
limit on the number of people who can attack particular
target. The Dragon-Blooded must pay 2 motes plus 1 mote
per targeted ally, and each ally will thereafter be able to
make an attack on the target, regardless of how defensible
the target’s position, provided that the ally is within normal
move distance of the target.
            </inner>
        </charme>


    </ability>

    <ability name="Occult">
        <charme>
            <title>
TERRESTRIAL CIRCLE SORCERY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1wp
Type: Permanent
Duration: Instant
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Occult 3
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blooded can cast spells of the Terrestrial
Circle
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Performance">
        <charme>
            <title>
MASTERFUL ENSEMBLE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Performance 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can divide up a number of dice
equal to his Intelligence + Performance dice pool among a
number of other, less talented performers. The cost is 1 mote
per performer plus 1 mote per die given to each performer.
The Dragon-Blood cannot give out more dice to a single
person than his own Performance rating or more than double
any one performer’s Performance rating.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SOUL-STIRRING PERFORMANCE METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Performance 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: A Dragon-Blooded performer can invoke a powerful
emotional response in her audience. The Dragon-Blood’s
player must roll (Charisma + Performance) and achieve one
success for every 10 people in the audience. If successful (and
the roll is all-or-nothing), the Dragon-Blooded can inspire
a deep-seated emotion in the audience. Mere mortals are
powerless to resist the effect, but persons with Essence ratings
higher than 1 may attempt to resist it with an appropriate
Virtue roll: Compassion for attempts to provoke anger,
Conviction for attempts to inspire sadness, Temperance for
attempts to provoke love and Valor for attempts to inspire
fear. Successes on the Virtue roll subtract from the Dragon-
CHAPTER ONE • THE DRAGON-BLOODED 33
Blooded’s net successes as to that person only. However, if
the emotion to be triggered resonates with a Solar’s primary
Virtue, the normal Limit Break rules apply.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
TALENTED IMPROVISATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Performance 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: There are a vast number of musical instruments in
creation, more than any single Exalt could ever completely
master. With this Charm, however, the Dragon-Blooded can
instantly become proficient (if not more) with any single
musical instrument. For the duration of the scene, the DragonBlooded can apply his Performance Ability without penalty
to any instrument he doesn’t know. He can also intuitively
understand forms of musical nota
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Presence">
        <charme>
            <title>
AUSPICIOUS FIRST MEETING ATTITUDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Refl exive
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Presence 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: In any non-combat, social situation, the Dragon-Blood
can intuitively adjust his behavior so as to make the best possible
fi rst impression with a particular individual who the Exalt is meeting for the fi rst time. Mechanically, the Dragon-Blooded gains
two extra dice to roll on every Bureaucracy, Presence or Socialize
roll during this fi rst encounter. If the Dragon-Blood deliberately
antagonizes the subject in anyway, the effect ends.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
GLOWING COAL RADIANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Presence 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: Until the Dragon-Blooded’s next action, anyone
attempting to attack or even look at him must score at least
one success on a Willpower roll.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
PASSION TRANSMUTING NUANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: Presence 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can transmute one strong passion
— lust, rage or terror — into one of the other two. She must
fi rst engage her target in conversation for a number of (10 – her
Essence) long ticks, and then, her player rolls (Manipulation
+ Presence) against a difficulty equal to the target’s Essence,
minus 1 for every point by which the Dragon-Blood’s Essence
exceeds the target’s. If successful, the Dragon-Blood gains two
dice on all subsequent social combat rolls against the target
designed to play off the target’s new emotional state.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Resistance">
        <charme>
            <title>
IMPERVIOUS SKIN OF STONE MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Resistance 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: Each mote spent (up to the maximum of her Essence)
will increase the Dragon-Blooded’s bashing and lethal soak
by 2.
            </inner>
        </charme>
        <charme>
            <title>
MOUNTAIN TOPPLING METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 4m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: One action
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Resistance 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For one action, the Dragon-Blooded’s Strength increases by 5, but only for the purpose of lifting or handling
stone or earthen objects, such as toppling pillars, hurling
boulders or stomping on the top of a hill to start a landslide.
Also, for the purposes of this Charm, jade-alloyed weapons
such as daiklaves are considered to be stone, and the Strength
bonus will apply to attacks made with such weapons.
            </inner>
        </charme>
        <charme>
            <title>
OX-BODY TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: N/A
Type: Special
Duration: Permanent
Combo: N/A
Minimum Ability: Resistance 1
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: Each time this Charm is taken (up to the maximum
of the Dragon-Blooded’s Resistance Ability), she gains one
-1 health level and one -2 health level.
            </inner>
        </charme>
        <charme>
            <title>
STRENGTH OF STONE TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m per person
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Resistance 2
Minimum Essence: 1
34
Effect: After a moment’s meditation, the Dragon-Blooded
adds one dot to his Strength and Stamina for the remainder of the scene. He can also add one dot in Strength and
Stamina to any number of additional people for 2 motes per
person. An individual can only benefit from this Charm
once per scene.
            </inner>
        </charme>
        <charme>
            <title>
UNEATING EARTH MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One day
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Resistance 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While this Charm is active, the Dragon-Blooded
does not require food or water. However, after (Essence +
Resistance) days, each additional day inflicts one level of
bashing damage on the Dragon-Blood, which cannot be
healed while the Charm is in use.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
UNSLEEPING EARTH MEDITATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Simple
Duration: One day
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Resistance 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While this Charm is in effect, the Dragon-Blooded
does not require sleep. However, after (Essence + Resistance) days, each additional day costs the Dragon-Blood 1
temporary Willpower, which cannot be regained while this
Charm is in use.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

    <ability name="Ride">

        <charme>
            <title>
CHARGE OF ONE HUNDRED GENERALS
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Supplemental
Duration: One charge
Combo: Yes
Minimum Abilities: Ride 3, War 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood must pay 1 Willpower plus 1 mote
per horse and rider affected, including the Dragon-Blood
herself. For the duration of a single charge, all of the riders
attack on the Dragon-Blood’s tick, and all of their attacks
are resolved before any delayed attack actions on the part of
the defenders. Furthermore, the player of any defender who
suffers damage must make any immediate Ride or Athletics
roll to avoid his character being dismounted or knocked
down. The Dragon-Blood must ride with the charging allies,
who cannot number more than (Essence x 5).
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DANCE OF THE JADE BRIDLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m + 1wp
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Special
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can tame virtually any animal
big enough to carry him and use it as a mount. The DragonBlood’s player must roll (Charisma + Ride), opposed by the
beast’s (Stamina + Willpower). The Dragon-Blood must
also roleplay “breaking” the mount, which, in the case of
very dangerous animals or flying creatures, can be quite
dangerous if the attempt fails. If the attempt succeeds, the
Dragon-Blood (and only the Dragon-Blood) can command
the creature and use it as a mount.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
EBONY SPUR TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: With this Charm, the Dragon-Blooded becomes more
efficient at employing the advantages of mounted combat.
After reflexively rolling Dexterity + Ride, the Dragon-Blooded
can add his Ride Ability to his damage dice in hand-to-hand
attacks made while mounted.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL HALO’S MERCY
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The baleful effects of the Dragon-Blooded anima
banners usually preclude the use of horses in combat situations. This Charm can alleviate those effects temporarily.
The Dragon-Blooded spends 3 motes while mounted, and
for one scene, the steed will suffer no wound effects from
his anima banner.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL HEART COMPANION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 5m (committed)
Type: Simple
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: While Elemental Halo’s Mercy will permit a mount to
resist the baleful effects of a Dragon-Blooded’s anima banner
for at least the duration of a combat, eventually, the mount
will die. Some Dragon-Blooded, however, have such close
CHAPTER ONE • THE DRAGON-BLOODED 35
relations with faithful steeds that the riders are unwilling to
see their mounts perish. With this Charm, a Dragon-Blood
can permanently attune herself to a particular mount (which
must also be a familiar) so that it is effectively a part of her.
While this Essence is committed, the mount is immune to the
anima fl ux of its Dragon-Blooded master (and only its master),
just as the Dragon-Blood’s personal possessions are.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
DRAGON-GRACED MOUNT
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: For the duration of the scene, the Dragon-Blood’s horse
gains the benefits of Elemental Heart Companion; this Charm
only costs 5 motes and a Willpower if the Dragon-Blood has
already committed 5 motes to the steed for the Elemental
Heart Companion Charm. More importantly, for the Charm’s
duration, the steed itself gains an elemental anima appropriate to the Dragon-Blood’s aspect, giving the animal special
abilities. The mounts of Air Aspects are immune to cold
and multiply their jumping distances by the rider’s Essence.
The mounts of Earth Aspects gain a bonus to bashing and
lethal soak equal to the rider’s Essence, and a mount can also
soak lethal damage with its full Stamina. The mounts of Fire
Aspects multiply their movement rate by the rider’s Essence.
The mounts of Water Aspects gain the ability to breathe and
complete freedom of movement while underwater, exactly
like the Water Aspect anima power. Finally, the mounts of
Wood can move through wooded areas without suffering any
penalty or decrease in movement rate, and a mount’s tracks
will be untraceable absent the use of Charms
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
HEAVEN-GRACED RIDING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Ride 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: For one action, the Dragon-Blooded may either add
his Ride Ability in yards to his mount’s movement rate,
or he can add that amount to the distance the mount can
safely jump.
            </inner>
    </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Sail">



        <charme>
            <title>
FINE PASSAGE NEGOTIATING STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Sail 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For the duration of a scene, the Dragon-Blooded
intuitively knows of any submerged hazards within fi ve miles
of her current location (assuming she is at sea, of course),
effectively adding three dice to any Sail rolls that involve
navigating through such hazards.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
HURRICANE PREDICTING GLANCE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Sail 2
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can predict the weather for the
next 24-hour period, although she cannot predict supernatural
changes to the weather made after her prediction.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
STORM-OUTRUNNING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Sail 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For the duration of a scene, the Dragon-Blooded can
double his ship’s rate of movement. While not a long-term
aid to travel, this Charm can ensure that one ship will beat
another into port or that the ship can outrun bad weather
or pirates.
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Socialize">

        <charme>
            <title>
FRIEND-TO-ALL-NATIONS ATTITUDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Socialize 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: If the Dragon-Blooded can speak the local language,
she can ignore any Social penalties caused by being a foreigner. Even if she cannot speak the local language, any
Social penalties caused by being a foreigner are reduced by
her Essence.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SWEETEN THE TAP METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Socialize 3
Minimum Essence: 1
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can increase the effects of alcohol
consumed in the area, reducing the difficulty of all Socialize
rolls by 1 for the scene.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WARM-FACED SEDUCTION STYLE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Socialize 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: During a seduction attempt only, the Dragon-Blood
can use this Charm to add fi ve dice to his Socialize Ability
or to double its normal rating, whichever is less.
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Stealth">
        <charme>
            <title>
DRAGON SHROUD TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3+m, 1wp
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Stealth 5
Minimum Essence: 4
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can bend light around himself,
conferring virtual invisibility. His identity is completely
concealed, and every 3 motes spent adds one automatic
success to Stealth-related rolls.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
FEELING-THE-AIR TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Stealth 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood retains total spatial awareness
even in total darkness. He cannot read or observe color, but
he can move freely and the Charm reduces blind-fighting
penalties by half.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
SOUNDLESS ACTION PRANA
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per minute
Type: Simple
Duration: Varies
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Stealth 3
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: For one minute per mote spent, the Dragon-Blooded
can eliminate any noise she directly produces, but not sounds
she causes that are not connected to her person. That is, she
could force open a door in complete silence, but if she threw a
rock through a window, the sound would be heard clearly.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WIND-WALKING TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: One day
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Survival 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: While this Charm is active, persons attempting to track
the Dragon-Blood without supernatural aid are completely
unable to do so. If the tracker is using supernatural aid, such
as Quarry Revelation Technique (see above), the two effects
cancel each other out, and normal tracking rules apply.
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="Thrown">
        <charme>
            <title>
INVISIBLY HIDDEN CHAKRAM METHOD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 4
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood may hide a number of weapons
elsewhere to be summoned back later. Each weapon costs 10
Essence and 1 Willpower. When the Dragon-Blood is ready
to attack, she can summon any or all of them and attack on
the same tick with her full (Dexterity + Thrown) pool. The
Dragon-Blood can hide as many as (Essence x 2) weapons.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
LOYAL WEAPON
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m
Type: Supplemental
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: Any weapon thrown by the Dragon-Blooded (including thrown melee weapons) will return to her hand by the
beginning of his next action.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
PERSISTENT HORNET ATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m
Type: Simple
Duration: (Essence) actions
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: After the Dragon-Blood throws a weapon at a target,
the weapon will continue to attack for (Essence) actions.
The weapon attacks on the Dragon-Blood’s tick, and the
Dragon-Blood’s player rolls (Perception + Thrown) for the
weapon to hit.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
VENGEFUL GUST COUNTERATTACK
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Reflexive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 4
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: If the Dragon-Blooded is the target of a ranged attack,
his player can opt to roll (Dexterity + Thrown) in place of
relying on the Exalt’s normal DV. Each success on this roll
subtracts from the attacker’s successes, and if his successes
exceed the attacker’s, the projectile reverses course, attacking his opponent with a number of attack dice equal to his
net successes.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WHIRLWIND SHIELD FORM
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can deflect ranged attacks aimed
at him or at allies at a cost of 3 motes plus 1 mote per each
ally protected. While the Charm is in effect, the DragonBlood’s Essence is automatically subtracted from any ranged
attack dice pools rolled against him or his allies, in addition
to the normal effects of DV.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WIND ARMOR TECHNIQUE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per 1L/1B
Type: Simple
Duration: Committed
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can fashion armor for herself out
of swirling air, adding 1L and 1B soak per mote spent. The
armor will last as long as the Essence is committed or until
the Dragon-Blood sleeps, whichever comes fi rst, and it is
fully compatible with normal armor.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
WIND WEAPONS
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 3m per weapon
Type: Simple
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: Thrown 5
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can fashion throwing weapons
from the very air itself. Each weapon has a base damage and
accuracy equal to the Dragon-Blood’s Essence and a range of
(Essence x 10) yards, and the Dragon-Blooded can create up
to (Essence) weapons in a tick. Once created, each weapon is
thrown refl exively with the Dragon-Blood’s full dice pool.
            </inner>
        </charme>
    </ability>
    <ability name="War">
        <charme>
            <title>
BLAZING COURAGEOUS SWORDSMEN INSPIRATION
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: Varies
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: War 3
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The Dragon-Blood spends 1 mote per warrior that
she commands, and each soldier will gain one additional -0
health level for the duration of the scene.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ELEMENTAL BATTLEFIELD
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 10m
Type: Simple
Duration: One scene
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: War 3
Minimum Essence: 3
Effect: The Dragon-Blood can impose his elemental anima
on a large area equal to his (Essence x 100) yards in radius
and centered on any outdoor location within his line of
sight. Anyone who comes within this area (which is most
commonly a battlefield of some sort) will suffer an environmental penalty on all actions equal to the Dragon-Blood’s
War Ability rating, as earth tremors, rainstorms, snow
flurries, clouds of acrid smoke or simply fast-growing briar
patches spring into existence to harry those caught within.
The exact effect depends on the Dragon-Blood’s aspect, but
the environmental penalty is the same, regardless of aspect.
Dragon-Blooded of the same aspect as the one who invoked
the Charm are immune to the environmental penalty, as are
any individuals attuned to him through the Charm Enfolded
in the Dragon’s Wings. Dragon-Blooded of other aspects are
immune if their animas are at the 8+ motes level.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
ENFOLDED IN THE DRAGON’S WINGS
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 1m per soldier
Type: Reflexive
Duration: One day
Combo: No
Minimum Ability: War 1
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: For each mote committed, the Dragon-Blooded
may temporarily render one soldier partially immune to the
damaging effects of her anima. Any damage inflicted on a
protected soldier by the Dragon-Blooded’s anima or by other
elemental effects attributable to her aspect is reduced by the
Dragon-Blood’s Essence. The nature of this Charm is such
that a Dragon-Blood can only protect a mortal soldier who is
considered “under her command.” Thus, neither bystanders
nor fellow Exalts can be protected by this Charm.
            </inner>
        </charme>

        <charme>
            <title>
PHANTOM-WARRIOR HORDE
            </title>
            <inner>
Cost: 2m
Type: Reflxive
Duration: Instant
Combo: Yes
Minimum Ability: War 2
Minimum Essence: 2
Effect: The area around the Dragon-Blooded appears to be
filled with warriors fashioned out of the element to which he
is aspected. While the phantoms are illusory, they are also
quite intimidating, and any enemy of the Dragon-Blooded
in the area must roll his Valor or be at -1 on all dice pools
for the next action. Mortals must score as many successes on
the Valor roll as the Dragon-Blood’s Presence, while beings
with an Essence higher than 1 need only one success.
 Charms denoted with an asterisk may only be used by
Dragon-Blooded with Immaculate training in the appropriate style.
            </inner>
        </charme>

    </ability>

</root>

